Tams-Witmark Collection
Music Division, Library of Congress
- Music (Box 1-829)
  - Reyer, (Louis-Etienne-) Ernest, 1823-1909
    - Sigurd. Paris: Ménéstrel, Heugel et Cie., n.d., Printed full score; Plate no. H and Cie 8954/G.H. 1519. (Box 467)
  - Rheinberger, Josef, 1839-1901
    - Klärchen auf Eberstein. Leipzig: Fr. Kistner, n.d., Printed full score; Plate no. 4887. (Box 468)
  - Ricci, Federico, 1809-1877, and Luigi, 1805-1859
    - Crispino e la comare, Manuscript full score; 4 vols. (Box 468-469)
  - Ricci, Federico, 1809-1877
    - La Prigione d'Edimburgo, Manuscript full score; 4 vols. (Box 470-471)
  - Richard, Ernst
    - Des Teufels Elixir, Manuscript score; 3 vols. (Box 167)
  - Rimsky-Korsakov, Nicolai Andreyevich, 1844-1908
    - Song of India. New York: Leo Feist, 1937, Printed part; 1st trombone part only; [Fragile]. (Box 200)
  - Robinson, William, 1839-1897
    - The Dude, Manuscript parts (Box 355)
  - Robyn, Alfred George, 1860-1935
    - The Princess beggar, Manuscript full score (Box 474)
    - Princess beggar, Manuscript full score; fragments and sketches (Box 475)
    - Princess beggar, Manuscript parts (Box 475)
    - Princess beggar, Manuscript full score; piano-vocal score; parts (Entrance of the Queen) only (Box 112)
    - Yankee tourist, Manuscript full score (incomplete) (Box 476)
    - Yankee tourist, Manuscript parts (one number only) (Box 476)
  - Römisch, Otto
    - Die Tolle Therese. Leipzig: W. Karczag, n.d., Printed piano-vocal score (from manuscript); Plate no. W. K. 976[T.]. (Box 816)
  - Roger, Victor, 1854-1903
    - [Vingt-huit jours de Clairette]
      - The Little trooper, Manuscript full score (Box 477)
  - Rossini, Gioacchino, 1792-1868
    - Il Barbiere di Siviglia*, Manuscript full score (incomplete) (Box 478)
    - Le Barbier de Seville, Printed full score; 2 vols. (incomplete); Plate no. 346. (Box 479)
    - Il Barbiere di Siviglia, Manuscript full score (incomplete) (Box 480)
    - Il Barbiere di Siviglia, Manuscript full score; Act I only (Box 481)
    - Il Barbiere di Siviglia, Manuscript score for strings; recitatives only (Box 481)
    - Il Barbiere di Siviglia, Manuscript full score; 2 vols. (Box 482)
    - La Cenerentola, Manuscript full score; Act I only (Box 483)
    - Cenerentola, Manuscript full score; Act I only (Box 484)
    - Cenerentola, Manuscript full score (Box 485)
    - La Cenerentola, Manuscript full score; Act II only; (2 copies). (Box 486)
    - La Donna del lago*, Manuscript full score; Act II only (Box 487)
    - La Donna del lago, Manuscript full score; 2 vols. (Box 488)
    - La Gazza ladra, Manuscript full score (incomplete) (Box 489)
    - La Gazza ladra, Manuscript full score; single number only; (2 copies). (Box 489)
    - La Gazza ladra, Manuscript parts (Box 490-491)
    - [Guillaume Tell]
      - Wilhelm Tell, Manuscript full score; 3 vols. (Box 492-494)
      - William Tell, Manuscript parts (Box 495-496)
      - Guglielmo Tell, Manuscript full score; 3 vols.; Acts I-II, IV only (Box 497-498)
      - Gulielmo Tell, Manuscript full score; 4 vols. (Box 499-501)
    - [Petite messe solennelle]
      - Messe solennelle. Paris: Brandus et Dufour, n.d., Printed full score; Plate no. B & D 11532. (Box 502)
      - Messa soleme, Manuscript parts (Box 503)
    - Otello, Manuscript parts (Box 504-507)
    - Otello, Manuscript full score; single number from Act III only (Box 508)
    - Otello, Manuscript full score; Act III only (Box 508)
    - La Pietra del paragone, Manuscript full score (Box 509-510)
    - Semiramide, Manuscript full score; Act II only (Box 511)
    - Semiramide, Manuscript full score; Act I, book 2 only (Box 512)
    - Semiramide, Manuscript full score; Introduzione only (Box 512)
    - Stabat mater. Paris: Troupenas, n.d., Printed parts; Plate nos. T. 1241 & 6589. (Box 513-514)
    - Stabat mater. Mainz: Schott, n.d., Printed full score; Plate no. 6588. (Box 515)
  - Roth, Louis, 1843-1929
    - Der Lieutenant zur See, Printed full score (lithograph); (2 copies). (Box 516)
    - Der Marquis von Rivoli, Printed full score (lithograph) (Box 517)
    - Der Polengraf, Printed full score (lithograph) (Box 518)
  - Saddler, Frank
    - Chapeaux de Paris, Manuscript full score (Box 518)
  - Saint-Saens, Camille, 1835-1921
    - Samson & Delilah, Manuscript full score; 3 vols. (Box 519-520)
    - Samson & Delilah, Manuscript full score; 3 vols. (Box 521)
  - Sauer, Willi
    - Casque D'or, Typed libretto (Box 816)
  - Schenk, Johann Baptist, 1753-1836
    - Der Dorfbarbier, Manuscript parts (Box 522)
    - Village barber*, Manuscript full score; Arrangement. (Box 523)
    - Der Dorfbarbier, Manuscript full score (Box 523)
  - Schmidt, Gustav, 1816-1882
    - [Prinz Eugen, der edle Ritter]
      - Prinz Eugen, Manuscript full score (Box 773)
  - Schmidt, Hermann, 1810-1845
    - Robert und Bertrand, Manuscript full score; 2 vols. (Box 524)
    - Robert und Bertram oder Die luftigen Vagabonden. Leipzig: Philipp Reclam Jun., n.d., Printed libretto; (1 complete copy; 3 incomplete copies). (Box 816)
  - Schmidt, Max
    - Gebirqsluft. Mühlhausen: G. Danner, n.d., Printed piano-vocal score (Box 816)
    - Gebirqsluft, Printed libretto (Box 816)
    - Der Kussentrakt, Manuscript piano-vocal score (Box 817)
  - Schneider, Louis
    - Kurmärker und Picarde, Manuscript libretto (Box 817)
  - Schubert, Franz
    - [Musikproben aus Hannerl und Schubert]
      - Hannerl. Hamburg: Vertrieb Deutscher Bühnenwerke, n.d., Printed piano-vocal score (missing pages) (Box 817)
    - Hannerl. Leipzig: W. Karczag, n.d., Printed piano-vocal score (incomplete); Plate no. W.K. 1332. (Box 817)
  - Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856
    - Manfred. Leipzig: Breitkopf & Härtel, n.d., Printed parts; Plate nos. orch. B. 936 and R.S. 87*(8)*. (Box 525-526)
    - Manfred. Leipzig: C.F. Peters, n.d., Printed full score (Box 527)
    - Manfred. Leipzig: Breitkopf & Härtel, n.d., Printed full score; Plate no. V.A. 849. (Box 527)
    - Manfred. Leipzig: Breitkopf & Härtel, n.d., Printed full score; Plate no. 10225. (Box 527)
    - Das Paradies und die Peri. Robert Schumann's Werke. Grössere Gesangwerke. Ser. 9, no. 79. Leipzig: Breitkopf & Härtel, n.d., Printed full score; Plate no. R.S. 79. (Box 527)
    - Requiem für Mignon. Robert Schumann's Werke. Grössere Gesangwerke. Ser. 9, no. 84. Leipzig: Breitkopf & Härtel, n.d., Printed full score; Plate no. R.S. 84. (Box 527)
    - Scenen aus Goethes Faust. Leipzig: C. F. Peters, n.d., Printed full score; Plate no. 4441. (Box 528)
  - Schwartz, Otto
    - Das Glücksmädel. Leipzig: Otto Teich, n.d., Printed piano-vocal score (Box 817)
    - Das Glücksmädel, Manuscript vocal part (Box 817)
  - Serpette, (Henri Charles Antoine) Gaston, 1846-1904
    - [Fanfreuluche]
      - Fanchonette*, Manuscript parts (Box 529)
      - Fanchonette*, Manuscript parts (Box 530)
      - Fanchonette/Fanfreuluche, Manuscript full score (Box 531)
    - [Petite chaperon rouge]
      - Little red riding hood, or the May Queen, Manuscript parts (Box 532)
      - Little red riding hood, Manuscript full score (Box 532)
  - Snaga, Joseph
    - Der Rodelzigeuner. Stuttgart: Julius Feuchtinger, n.d., Printed piano-vocal score; Plate no. J.F. 2104.; (6 copies: 3 complete scores; 3 incomplete scores). (Box 817)
    - Der Rodelzigeuner, Printed parts (from manuscript) (Box 818)
    - Der Rodelzigeuner, Printed vocal parts (from manuscript) (Box 818)
    - Der Rodelzigeuner, Printed libretto (Box 818)
  - Solomon, Edward, 1855-1895
    - Billie Taylor, Manuscript parts (Box 534-535)
    - Billie Taylor, Manuscript parts (Box 536)
    - Claude Duval, Manuscript parts (Box 537)
    - [Polly, the pet of the regiment]
      - Polly, Manuscript full score (incomplete) (Box 538)
      - Polly, Manuscript parts (Box 538)
      - Polly, Manuscript parts (Box 539)
      - Polly, Manuscript parts (Box 540)
    - Red hussar, Manuscript parts (Box 541)
    - Virginia, Manuscript parts (Box 542)
  - Solomon, Fred
    - King Kalico, Manuscript full score (Box 543)
  - Spenser, Willard
    - The Princess Bonnie, Manuscript full score (Box 544)
  - Spohr, Louis, 1784-1859
    - Jessonda. Leipzig: C. F. Peters, n.d., Printed full score; Plate no. 6489. (Box 547)
  - Spontini, Gaspare, 1774-1851
    - La Vestale*, Manuscript full score; 2 vols. (Box 548)
  - Stahl, Richard, 1860-1899
    - Said Pasha, Manuscript full score; Arranged by Edwin Price. (Box 549)
    - Said Pasha, Manuscript parts [set 1] (Box 550)
    - Said Pasha, Manuscript parts [set 2] (Box 551)
    - Said Pasha, Manuscript parts [set 3] (Box 552)
    - Said Pasha, Manuscript parts [set 5] (Box 553-554)
    - Said Pasha, Manuscript parts [set 6] (Box 555)
    - Said Pasha, Manuscript parts [set 7] (Box 556)
  - Stanford, Charles Villiers, Sir, 1852-1924
    - Phaudrig Crohoore. London: Boosey, 1896, Printed full score (Box 549)
  - Steffens, G.
    - Die Schöne Ungarin, Printed piano-vocal score; 2 p. piano-vocal score titled Einlage laid in. (Box 819)
    - Die Schöne Ungarin, Manuscript parts (Box 819)
    - Die Schöne Ungarin, Manuscript vocal parts (Box 819)
    - Die Schöne Ungarin. Leipzig: Philipp Reclam Jun., n.d., Printed libretto (Box 819)
    - Die Schöne Ungarin, Miscellaneous (Box 819)
  - Stein, Karl, 1797-1863
    - Versprechen hinterin Heerd, Manuscript full score (Box 557)
  - Stiegmann, Eduard, d. 1880
    - Das Mädchen vom Dorfe, Manuscript full score; no. 9 only (Box 557)
    - Das Mädchen vom Dorfe, Manuscript full score (Box 557)
    - Die Töchter Lucifers, Manuscript full score; 2 vols. (Box 557)
  - Strasser, Alfred, and Weinzierl, Max von, 1841-1898
    - Fioretta. Vienna: Stratzer, n.d., Printed full score (lithograph) (Box 558)
  - Straus, Oscar
    - Ein Walzertraum. Leipzig-Wien: Ludwig Doblinger, n.d., Printed piano-vocal score (songs 1-7 only); Plate no. M.F.A. 158. (Box 820)
    - Ein Walzertraum, Manuscript and lithograph vocal parts (Box 820)
    - Ein Walzertraum, Manuscript parts (2 folders) (Box 820)
    - Ein Walzertraum, Printed libretto; Additional material laid in. (Box 820)
    - Ein Walzertraum, Miscellaneous (Box 820)
  - Strauss, Johann, Jr. 1825-1899
    - Blinde Kuh*, Manuscript full score; [Fragile]. (Box 559)
    - Die Fledermaus, Manuscript full score (Box 560)
    - Die Fledermaus, Manuscript full score; 3 vols. (Box 561-562)
    - Die Fledermaus. Leipzig: Aug. Cranz, n.d., Printed piano-vocal score; Plate no. F.S. 23422. (Box 821)
    - Die Fledermaus, Manuscript parts (Box 821)
    - [Indigo und die vierzig Räuber]
      - Königin Indigo, Manuscript full score; [Fragile]. (Box 563)
      - Indigo*, Manuscript full score; [Fragile]. (Box 564)
    - Jabuka, Manuscript full score (Box 565)
    - Der Carnival in Rom*, Manuscript full score (Box 566)
    - Der Lustige Krieg, or Merry war*, Printed full score (lithograph) (Box 567)
    - Der Lustige Krieg, or Merry war*, Printed full score (lithograph); [Fragile]. (Box 568)
    - The Merry war, Manuscript parts (Box 569)
    - The Merry war, Manuscript parts (Box 570)
    - A Night in Venice, Printed full score (lithograph); [Fragile]. (Box 571)
    - A Night in Venice, Printed full score (lithograph); 2 vols. (Box 571)
    - Eine Nacht in Venedig, Printed full score (lithograph) (Box 572)
    - Eine Nacht in Venedig, Manuscript parts (Box 822)
    - Prince Methusalem*, Mimeographed parts (vocal) (Box 573)
    - Prinz Methusalem, Printed full score (lithograph) (Box 574)
    - Simplicius, Printed full score (lithograph); [Fragile - Both copies].; (2 copies). (Box 575)
    - Simplicius, Printed full score (lithograph)(incomplete); [Fragile]. (Box 576)
    - Spitzentuch der Königen, Printed full score (lithograph) (Box 577)
    - Queen's lace handkerchief, Manuscript parts (Box 578)
    - Wiener-Blut. n.p., n.d., Printed piano-vocal score; Manuscript 1 page sketch laid in.; Plate no. 39958.40791.; [Fragile]. (Box 822)
    - Wiener-Blut, Manuscript parts (2 folders); Additional material laid in. (Box 822-823)
    - Wiener-Blut, Manuscript and printed vocal parts; [Fragile]. (Box 823)
    - Wiener-Blut, Manuscript synopsis (Box 823)
    - Wiener-Blut, Manuscript (unidentified sketch) (Box 823)
    - Zigeunerbaron, Printed stage band score (lithograph) (Box 579)
    - Zigeuner Baron, Printed full score (lithograph) (Box 579)
    - Der Zigeunerbaron. Leipzig: n.p., n.d., Manuscript and printed parts; Plate no. C. 26794 (incomplete). (Box 823)
  - Stuart, Leslie [Barrett, Thomas Augustine], 1866-1928
    - Silver slipper*, Manuscript full score (Box 580)
  - Sullivan, Arthur, Sir, 1842-1900
    - Contrabandista*, Manuscript full score; Arranged by W. C. Parker. (Box 581)
    - H. M. S. Pinafore, Manuscript full score; Arranged by Edwin A. Price. (Box 582)
    - Pinafore, Manuscript full score; Act I only (Box 582)
    - Pinafore, Manuscript score for military band (Box 583)
    - Mikado, Manuscript parts (Box 583)
    - Mikado, Manuscript full score (Box 584)
    - Patience, Manuscript stage band score (Box 585)
    - Patience, Manuscript full score (Box 585)
  - Suppé, Franz von, 1819-1895
    - Afrikareise. Hamburg: Cranz, n.d., Printed full score (lithograph) (Box 586)
    - A Trip to Africa, Manuscript parts (Box 587)
    - Die Afrikareise/Voyage in Le Afrique. Hamburg: Cranz, n.d., Printed parts (lithograph) (Box 588)
    - Die Africareise, Manuscript full score (lithograph); (2 copies). (Box 589)
    - Die Africareise*. Hamburg: Cranz, n.d., Printed full score (lithograph) (Box 777)
    - Bellman, Manuscript parts; Arranged by Wm. Corner. (Box 590-592)
    - Bellman, Printed full score (lithograph) (Box 593)
    - Otto Bellmann*, Manuscript full score (incomplete) (Box 593)
    - Boccaccio, Manuscript full score; 2 vols. (Box 594)
    - Boccaccio. Hamburg: Cranz, n.d., Printed full score (lithograph) (Box 595)
    - Boccaccio*, Printed full score (lithograph); [Fragile]. (Box 596)
    - Donna Juanita, Printed full score (lithograph) (Box 597)
    - Fatanitza, Manuscript parts (Box 598)
    - Fatanitza*, Printed full score (lithograph) (Box 599)
    - Fatanitza, Manuscript parts (Box 600)
    - Fatanitza, Manuscript full score (Box 601)
    - Fatanitza, Manuscript full score; 2 vols. (Box 602)
    - Fatanitza, Printed full score (lithograph) (Box 603)
    - Fatanitza*, Printed full score (lithograph); [Fragile]. (Box 604)
    - Flotte Bursche, Manuscript full score; (2 copies - both missing overture). (Box 605)
    - Franz Schubert, Manuscript full score (Box 606)
    - Die Frau Meisterin, Manuscript full score (Box 607)
    - Der Gascogner, Printed full score (lithograph) (Box 607)
    - Herzblättchen, Manuscript full score (lithograph); [Fragile]. (Box 608)
    - Clover/Jagd nach dem Glück*, Printed full score (lithograph) (Box 609)
    - Jagd nach dem Glück. Hamburg: Cranz, n.d., Printed full score (lithograph) (Box 609)
    - Die Jagd nach dem Glück. Hamburg: Cranz, n.d., Printed full score (lithograph) (Box 610)
    - Die Jagd nach dem Glück. Hamburg: Cranz, n.d., Manuscript full score; Act I only (Box 610)
    - Die Jagd nach dem Gluck. Hamburg: Cranz, n.d., Printed parts (lithograph) (Box 611-613)
    - The Clover, Manuscript full score; parts (Box 614)
    - The Clover, Manuscript full score; 2 vols. (Box 614)
    - Leichte Cavallerie, Manuscript parts (Box 615)
    - Leichte Cavallerie, Manuscript full score (Box 616)
    - Leichte Cavallerie, Printed full score (lithograph) (Box 616)
    - Lohengelb, Manuscript parts (Box 617-618)
    - Lohengelb, Manuscript full score (Box 619)
    - Der Matrosen Heimkehr/Sailor's return, Manuscript full score (Box 620)
    - Das Pensionat, Manuscript full score (Box 621)
    - Das Pensionat. Vienna: Böhm, n.d., Printed full score (lithograph); (2 copies). (Box 621)
    - Die Schöne Galathé, Manuscript full score (Box 622)
    - The Lovely Galatea, Manuscript full score; overture only; Arranged by W. C. Parker. (Box 622)
    - Die Schöne Galatea, Manuscript full score (Box 622)
    - Vineta, Manuscript full score (Box 623)
    - Zehn Mädchen und kein Mann, Manuscript full score; (2 copies). (Box 623)
    - Zehn Mädchen und kein Mann, Printed part (violin I only); Plate no. 8440-50. (Box 623)
    - Zehn Mädchen und kein Mann. Leipzig: Cranz, n.d., Printed piano-vocal score; Plate no. 12685. (Box 824)
    - Zehn Mädchen und kein Mann, Manuscript parts (2 folders) (Box 824)
    - Zehn Mädchen und kein Mann, Manuscript vocal parts (Box 825)
    - Zehn Mädchen und kein Mann, Miscellaneous (Box 825)
  - Talbot, Howard, 1865-1929
    - A Chinese honeymoon*, Manuscript full score (Box 624)
  - Tchaikovsky, Piotr Ilyich, 1840-1893
    - Pikovaia dama. Moscow: Jurgenson, n.d., Printed full score; Plate no. 34683. (Box 628)
  - Teich, Otto [Music publisher, Leipzig]
    - Rheinische Liebe, Rheinischer Wein. Leipzig: Otto Teich, n.d., Printed libretto (Box 825)
  - Thiem, Alfredo
    - Weltkrieg, Manuscript piano-vocal score; Manuscript piano score and manuscript material laid in. (Box 825)
  - Thiem, Hans
    - Lehmann's Orientreise, Printed libretto (Box 825)
    - Lehmann's Orientreise, Typed parts (Box 825)
  - Thomas, Ambroise, 1811-1896
    - La Double echelle. Paris: Lemoine et Cie., n.d., Printed full score; Plate no. L. et Cie. 1011. (Box 628)
    - Migon, Manuscript full score (Box 625)
    - Migon. n.p.: M. Ménéstral, Heugel, et Cie., n.d., Manuscript full score (printed overture); 3 vols.; Plate no. H. 4682 (O). (Box 626-627)
    - [Pygmalion and Galatea]
      - Pygmalian, Manuscript full score (Box 627)
  - Thompson, Lewis Sabin, 1868-1908, and Barnet, R(obert) A(yres), 1850-1933
    - Baron Humbug, Manuscript full score (Box 629)
  - Tracy, George Lowell
    - Excelsior, Jr., Manuscript full score (Box 630)
  - Unzengruber, Ludwig
    - Der G'wissenswurm, Manuscript piano-vocal score (Box 826)
    - Der G'wissenswurm. Stuttgart: J. Gotta'fche Buchhandlung Nachfolger G.m.b.S., 1901, Printed libretto (Box 826)
    - Der G'wissenswurm, Printed parts (Box 826)
    - Der G'wissenswurm, Manuscript synopsis (Box 826)
    - Der G'wissenswurm, Miscellaneous (Box 826)
  - Vaccai, Nicola, 1790-1848
    - Giulietta & Romeo, Manuscript full score; Tomb scene only (Box 631)
  - Varney, Louis, 1844-1908
    - [Mousquetaires au couvent]
      - The Musketeers, Manuscript parts (Box 632)
      - The Musketeers, Manuscript full score (Box 633)
  - Varnum, [?]
    - The Crowing hen, Manuscript vocal parts (Box 633)
  - Vasseur, Léon, 1844-1917
    - La Timbale d'argent, Manuscript parts (Box 635)
  - Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901
    - Aida, Manuscript stage band score; 2 vols. (Box 636)
    - Aida. Milan: G. Ricordi, 1913, Printed full score; Plate no. 113954.; (4 copies). (Box 636)
    - Aida, Manuscript full score; 2 vols. (Box OV-637-638)
    - Attila, Manuscript full score; Acts I-II only (Box 638)
    - Un Ballo in maschera. Milan: G. Ricordi, 1914, Printed full score; Plate no. 113959. (Box 639)
    - Un Ballo in maschera, Manuscript full score; 3 vols. (Box 639-640)
    - Un Ballo in maschera, Manuscript stage band score (Box 639-640)
    - Ernani, Manuscript full score; 4 vols. (Box 641)
    - Ernani, Manuscript stage band score (Box 641)
    - Ernani, Manuscript full score; 2 vols. (Box 642-643)
    - Ernani, Manuscript stage band score (Box 643)
    - La Forza del destino, Manuscript full score; 4 vols. (Box 644-647)
    - Luisa Miller, Manuscript full score; 3 vols. (Box 648)
    - Nabucco, Manuscript full score; 2 vols. (Box 649)
    - [Otello]
      - Othello, Manuscript full score; 4 vols. (Box 650)
      - Othello, Manuscript stage band score (Box 650)
    - Rigoletto, Manuscript full score; 4 vols. (Box 651)
    - Rigoletto, Manuscript stage band score (Box 651)
    - Rigoletto, Manuscript full score; 3 vols. (Box 652)
    - Rigoletto, Manuscript stage band score (Box 652)
    - Rigoletto, Manuscript full score (condensed); Act I only (Box 653)
    - Rigoletto, Manuscript stage band score (Box 653)
    - Rigoletto. Milan: Ricordi, n.d., Printed stage band score; Act I only; Plate no. D 54295 D. (Box 653)
    - Rigoletto, Manuscript full score; Acts I-II only (Box 654)
    - Rigoletto. Milan: Ricordi, 1914, Printed full score; 2 vols.; Plate no. 113960. (Box 655)
    - La Traviata. Milan: Ricordi, 1914, Manuscript full score; Act I only; Plate no. 113958. (Box 656)
    - La Traviata. Milan: Ricordi, n.d., Printed stage band score; Plate no. 21367 E. (Box 656)
    - Il Trovatore. Milan: Ricordi, 1913, Printed full score; Plate no. 113957. (Box 657)
    - Il Trovatore, Manuscript full score (condensed) (Box 658)
    - Il Trovatore, Manuscript full score; 2 vols. (Box 659)
    - Il Trovatore, Manuscript full score; 2 vols. (Box 660-661)
  - Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883
    - [Fliegende Holländer]
      - The Flying Dutchman, Manuscript full score (printed overture - Leipzig: n.p., n.d.); 3 vols.; Plate no. H.M. 671. (Box 662-663)
    - Götterdämmerung. Mainz: Schott, n.d., Printed full score; Plate no. 21953. (Box 704)
    - Götterdämmerung. Mainz: Schott, n.d., Manuscript full score; single number only; Plate no. 27004 a/b/c. (Box 705)
    - Lohengrin. Neue Ausgabe. Leipzig: Breitkopf & Härtel, 1887, Printed full score; Plate no. 15451. (Box 664)
    - Lohengrin. Neue Ausgabe. Leipzig: Breitkopf & Härtel, 1887, Printed full score; Plate no. 15451. (Box 665)
    - Lohengrin. Neue Ausgabe. Leipzig: Breitkopf & Härtel, 1887, Printed full score; Plate no. 15451. (Box OV-667)
    - Lohengrin, Printed full score (lithograph) (Box OV-667)
    - Lohengrin, Printed full score (lithograph); Act I only (Box OV-668)
    - Lohengrin, Printed full score (lithograph); Acts II-III only (Box OV-668)
    - Lohengrin, Manuscript full score; for winds only (Box 666)
    - Meistersinger von Nürnberg. Mainz: Schott, n.d., Printed full score; Plate no. 18469. (Box 669)
    - Die Meistersinger von Nürnberg, Manuscript parts [set 2] (Box 670-677)
    - Meistersinger, Manuscript parts [set 2] (Box 768)
    - Parsifal, Manuscript full score (printed prelude); 3 vols. (Box 678)
    - Parsifal. Mainz: Schott, n.d., Manuscript full score (printed prelude); 3 vols.; Plate no. 23571. (Box 680-681)
    - Parsifal. Mainz: Schott, n.d., Manuscript parts (printed prelude); Plate no. 23576. (Box 682-685)
    - Parsifal. Mainz: Schott, n.d., Manuscript full score (printed prelude); Plate no. 23571. (Box 686-687)
    - Parsifal. Mainz: Schott, n.d., Printed full score; 3 vols.; Plate no. 23571. (Box 687-688)
    - Parsifal. Mainz: Schott, n.d., Printed full score; 3 vols.; Plate no. 27200 a/b/c. (Box 689)
    - Das Rheingold. Mainz: Schott, n.d., Printed full score; Plate no. 20800. (Box 697)
    - Rienzi. Berlin: Meser, 1886, Printed full score (lithograph); Acts III-IV only (Box 690)
    - Rienzi, Manuscript parts (Box 691-695)
    - Siegfried. Mainz: Schott, n.d., Printed full score; Plate no. 21544. (Box 703)
    - Tannhäuser. Dresden: n.p., 1845, Printed full score (lithograph) (Box 706)
    - Tannhäuser, Manuscript full score; Arranged for winds only. (Box 707)
    - Tannhäuser. Leipzig: C. F. Peters, n.d., Printed full score; 3 vols.; Plate no. 10352. (Box 708)
    - Tannhäuser, Manuscript full score; 3 vols. (Box 709)
    - Tannhäuser. Paris: Durand, n.d., Printed full score; Act I only; Plate no. D.S. 4332. (Box 710)
    - Tristan und Isolde. Leipzig: Breitkopf & Härtel, n.d., Printed full score; Plate no. 10000. (Box 711)
    - Tristan und Isolde. Leipzig: Breitkopf & Härtel, n.d., Printed full score; Plate no. 10000. (Box 712)
    - Die Walküre. Mainz: Schott, n.d., Printed full score; 2 vols.; Plate no. 21170. (Box 698)
    - Die Walküre. Mainz: Schott, n.d., Printed full score; 3 vols.; Plate no. 21170. (Box 699-701)
    - Die Walküre, Printed full score; Act II only (Box 702)
  - Wahnecke, Richard
    - Durch [Freunde] Schuld, Manuscript full score (Box 826)
  - Wallace, (William) Vincent, 1812-1865